[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 20]
[제20화]
Don't let what happened to Jason
제이슨에게 일어난 일이
happen to another child.
다른 아이에게 반복되게 하지 마세요
Take good care of your students.
학생들 잘 챙겨 주시고요
[Little Savage Tribe]
[야인 부족]
All players, gather at the school field.
전원 운동장으로 집합!
Why do you think
이 밤중에
Coach called us here so late at night?
코치님이 왜 우리를 부르셨을까?
He loves us too much.
우릴 사랑하니까!
Coach is here.
코치님 오신다
Hello, Coach.
코치님 안녕하세요
-Hello, Coach. -Coach.
- 코치님, 안녕하세요
Coach,
코치님
calling us here so late,
설마 훈련시키려고
it can't be for training, right?
이 시간에 부른 건 아니시죠?
We're all dressed up.
저희 다 이렇게 잔뜩 멋 부렸는데
How can we train like this?
훈련을 어떻게 해요?
It's not training.
오늘 훈련 안 해
Then why are we here?
그럼 무슨 일이죠?
Just to chat.
그냥 얘기나 좀 하자
-A chat. -OK.
- 얘기요? - 네
Who cares?
괜찮아
-A chat! -Let's have a chat.
- 그러죠, 뭐 - 말씀하세요
Coach,
코치님
why are you so shy today?
오늘 왜 이렇게 부끄러워하세요?
Have a seat, Coach.
앉으세요
First of all, I want to
우선 오늘
reintroduce myself.
내 소개를 다시 해볼까 해
I'm Wang Fa.
내 이름은 왕파
I'm a huge failure as a coach.
아주 실패한 코치지
Because an excellent player
예전에 내가 가르쳤던
I used to coach
아주 뛰어난 선수가
chose to
내 앞에서
end his life right in front of me.
스스로 목숨을 끊었거든
In the past, I only cared about winning
예전의 난 승패에만 신경 썼고
and about football skills.
실력만 중요하게 생각했어
So I really did neglect his inner feelings.
그래서 그 아이의 마음을 외면했던 게 사실이야
So much so that when he was
걔가 약물을 썼다고
suspected of doping,
의심받고
when he became a target of public criticism,
모두의 비난을 받을 때
I wasn't a coach who believed him unconditionally.
무조건 그 애를 믿어 주는 코치가 되어 주지 못했어
Coach,
코치님
when he faced all this,
그 선수가 그런 일을 겪었을 때
how old was he?
몇 살이었나요?
Sixteen.
열여섯 살
A year younger than us now.
지금 우리보다도 한 살 어리네요
Why are you suddenly telling us this?
갑자기 왜 저희한테 그런 말씀을 하세요?
Because I want to tell you...
절대 포기하지 말라고
not to give up.
너희한테 말해 주고 싶어서
On the field,
경기장에서는 당연히
of course we can't
이기겠다는 신념을
give up the belief that we must win.
버려서는 안 돼
But off the field...
하지만 경기장 밖에는…
Boys,
얘들아
off the field,
경기장 밖에는
there are so many things
축구보다 중요한 것들이
far more important than football.
정말 너무나도 많아
So what I want to say is,
그래서 내가 하고 싶은 말은
no matter what you encounter,
앞으로 무슨 일을 겪든
never give up on yourselves.
너희 자신을 포기하지 마
Never give up on yourselves.
포기하면 안 돼
Never give up on yourselves!
절대 안 돼
From this moment on,
지금 이 순간부터
I'll always be your coach.
난 영원히 너희들의 코치다
Believe that
날 믿어줘
no matter what you encounter,
앞으로 너희가 무슨 일을 겪든
I'll try my best to share your burden.
내가 최선을 다해 짐을 덜어 줄게
And I'll never give up on you.
그리고 난 너희를 포기하지 않을 거야
If one day I'm gone,
만약 언젠가 내가 없다면
it's only because you're strong enough
그건 너희가 충분히 강해져서
and don't need me anymore.
더는 내가 필요 없기 때문일 거야
I look forward to that day.
난 그날을 기대하고 있어
I'm done.
내 얘긴 여기까지야
Class is over. Dismissed.
수업 끝, 해산!
Sorry for calling you out so late.
늦게 불러내서 미안하다
Hurry back to sleep.
얼른 들어가서 자
We have training tomorrow.
내일 또 훈련해야지
Coach.
코치님
You still have us!
코치님껜 저희가 있잖아요
See you tomorrow!
내일 봬요
-Yeah. -See you tomorrow!
- 그래요 - 내일 봬요
-See you tomorrow, Coach!
- 내일 봬요, 코치님
-We're here! -See you tomorrow, Coach.
- 저희가 있잖아요
See you tomorrow, Coach.
내일 봬요
♪ Time's passing by ♪
♪ 세월은 물처럼 ♪
See you tomorrow.
내일 보자
♪ Nothing remains ♪
♪ 흔적도 없이 흘러가고 ♪
♪ All the dreamers awake alone ♪
♪ 함께 꿈꾸던 우리 쉽사리 잠들지 못하네 ♪
See you tomorrow.
내일 봐
♪ Shadows above ♪
♪ 때로는 먹구름이 드리우고 ♪
♪ Rain falls around ♪
♪ 축축한 빗물이 삶의 구석구석을 적셔도 ♪
♪ In your arms ♪
♪ 네 품 안에서 ♪
♪ We become one ♪
♪ 평행하던 우리 세상은 마침내 하나가 돼 ♪
Before he jumped off the roof,
옥상에서 뛰어내리기 전까지
he must've struggled a lot.
분명 한참을 괴로워했겠죠
[Superstar Slacker]
[느긋한 초신성]
Ms. Ju Li?
쥐리 선생님
Wanxing isn't answering my calls or messages.
완싱이 전화를 안 받고 문자도 답이 없는데
Do you know where she went?
어디 갔는지 아세요?
Lin Wanxing!
린완싱
Let's end it?
끝내자?
Then let's end it.
그만 끝내자
And I don't hope to see you again.
다신 보고 싶지도 않아
Starting from the highest point,
가장 높은 곳에서 출발하면
I can at least feel like I'm flying for a few seconds.
적어도 몇 초는 나는 기분을 느낄 수 있겠지
Split up and look for tall buildings nearby.
근처 높은 건물들부터 찾아 봐요
Heads: move forward.
앞면이면 앞으로 가고
Tails:
뒷면이면
stay here.
남는 거야
Lin Wanxing,
린완싱
good thing you backed out on it then.
그때 네가 반칙해서 다행이다
Lin Wanxing!
린완싱!
Wang Fa.
왕파
Lin Wanxing.
린완싱
Since you backed out on it,
반칙한 김에
you should stick to it to the end.
끝까지 반칙해요
I was so worried about you,
걱정했잖아요
afraid you'd do something stupid.
당신이 나쁜 생각 할까 봐
Don't worry.
걱정 마요
I wasn't going to do anything stupid.
나쁜 생각 안 했어요
I wrote this postcard
이 엽서는
a year ago.
1년 전에 내가 쓴 거예요
♪ Waiting for a dark cloud to pass by you ♪
♪ 먹구름 한 조각이 네 곁을 지나갈 때 ♪
I came up here today
오늘 여기 올라온 건
just to get some fresh air
그냥 바람 좀 쐬고 싶어서예요
and reflect on the past.
지난 일을 반성할 겸
♪ Listen closely to its cries ♪
♪ 그 울음소리에 귀 기울여 봐 ♪
Really,
진짜예요
I'm not lying to you.
거짓말 아닌데
♪ The heavy rain will wash away your reflection ♪
♪ 장대비가 네 그림자를 데려가 ♪
After all, life is too precious
생명은 소중하잖아요
to give up so easily,
쉽게 포기하면 안 되죠
♪ And carry it toward distant scenery ♪
♪ 먼 곳의 풍경을 찾아 떠날 거야 ♪
right?
그렇죠?
Thank you for not giving up easily.
쉽게 포기하지 않아 줘서 고마워요
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ 모든 경험에는 저마다의 의미가 있어 ♪
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 장면 하나하나가 모여 지금의 나를 이루지 ♪
Stay in the wind any longer, and you'll catch a cold.
더 있다간 감기 걸리겠어요
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 상처가 흉터로 남는다 해도 ♪
Let's go back.
이제 들어가죠
Wait.
잠깐만요
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 날 치유하는 법을 배웠어 ♪
♪ The love I have given, the love I have received ♪
♪ 내가 준 사랑 내가 받은 사랑 ♪
♪ Every one of them gives me the strength not to fear being hurt ♪
♪ 그 모든 게 날 강하게 해 ♪
♪ Let my tears be carried away, back into the ocean ♪
♪ 내 눈물을 바다로 흘려보내 ♪
The wind is very gentle tonight.
오늘따라 밤바람이 참 부드럽네
♪ And blown toward flowers blooming far away ♪
♪ 저 멀리 꽃 피는 곳으로 불어가 ♪
Let everything go with it.
모든 걸 그냥 날려 보내자
♪ I fill the blank spaces of life with colors ♪
♪ 빈 마음을 색으로 채워 가 ♪
♪ My dreams are not afraid to awaken; they continue to exist ♪
♪ 내 꿈은 깨어나도 사라지지 않아 ♪
Finally, Wanxing has someone protecting her.
드디어 완싱을 지켜주는 사람이 생겼네
That's great.
다행이다
♪ I go beyond the dark clouds and feel the haze disperse ♪
♪ 먹구름 너머 걷히는 하늘을 느껴 봐 ♪
♪ Let me understand myself more clearly ♪
♪ 날 더 잘 알게 될 테니까♪
What's that sound?
무슨 소리죠?
♪ Take away my reflection ♪
♪ 내 그림자를 데려가 ♪
♪ And go in search of distant scenery ♪
♪ 저 먼 풍경을 찾아 ♪
It's so dirty.
더러워
Don't eat that.
먹으면 안 돼
Its leg is injured.
발을 다쳤네요
It needs to go to the vet.
병원에 가야 해요
I'll call a cab.
택시 부를게요
Thank you for sending me back.
데려다줘서 고마워요
Good night.
잘 자요
Wait.
잠깐만요
Since you said
나한테
good night to me,
잘 자라고 한 거
can I take it that
날 용서했다는 뜻으로
you've forgiven me?
이해해도 될까요?
My motives were impure.
내가 불순한 의도로
Approaching you and investigating you,
접근하고 조사해서
it disappointed you, right?
실망했죠?
I admit that
인정해요
before, I did think
전에는 정말 그렇게 생각했어요
we shouldn't
더는
stay in touch anymore.
연락할 필요도 없다고 말이죠
"Before"?
전에요?
What about now?
그럼 지금은요?
During this time,
요 며칠
I've thought a lot.
나도 생각 많이 했어요
It's understandable that
당신이 날 조사한 건
you'd investigate me.
탓할 수 없는 일이에요
If I were in your shoes,
나였어도
I'd have done the same.
그랬을 거니까요
It's just...
다만…
I clearly had so many chances
진실을 말할 기회가
to tell you the truth,
많았는데
but I didn't.
그러지 못했어요
It made you feel that
진심으로 믿는 게
I didn't really trust you.
아니라고 생각했겠죠
Right?
맞나요?
But it wasn't that I didn't trust you.
근데 당신을 못 믿은 게 아니라
I was just afraid...
그냥 두려웠어요
Afraid you'd push me away.
당신이 날 밀어낼까 봐요
I didn't want you to hate me.
미움받고 싶지 않았어요
But in the end, I still ended up hurting you.
하지만 결국 당신을 속상하게 만들었네요
I'm sorry.
미안해요
But if you're still willing to trust me,
그래도 날 다시 믿어 준다면
I'll hold nothing back from you
앞으로는 절대
from now on.
아무것도 숨기지 않을게요
You can be completely honest with me,
당신은 나한테 절대적으로 솔직할지 모르겠지만
but I can't do the same.
난 그렇게 못 해요
There are still many things
아직도 말하기 싫은 일들이
I don't want to talk about.
많거든요
It's OK.
괜찮아요
That sentence alone is honest enough.
그 말만으로도 충분히 솔직한걸요
Demanding absolute trust from others
남한테는 절대적인 믿음을 요구하면서
while keeping things hidden myself,
정작 본인은 숨기고
aren't you bothered by
이렇게 이중 잣대인데
my double standards?
정말 괜찮아요?
You have the right to keep secrets.
당신은 비밀을 간직할 권리가 있어요
Is there anything else?
또 볼일이 남았나요?
It needs a bath.
얘 목욕시켜야죠
You can't handle it alone.
혼자서는 힘들 거예요
I have a bathtub.
우리 집에 욕조가 있어서
It'll be easier.
씻기기 편해요
You...
저…
I can help.
도울 수 있어요
All done.
됐어요
Me too?
나도 해주게요?
Aren't you hurt too?
당신도 다쳤잖아요
Come, let me see.
이리 와, 어디 보자
Does your paw hurt?
발 안 아파?
Cover its eyes.
얘 눈 좀 가려 줘요
OK.
네
Make sure to wash behind its ears.
귀 뒤쪽을 잘 씻겨야 해요
It's been scratching there.
아까부터 계속 긁던데
Here, be good. Close your eyes.
착하지, 눈 감자
Close your eyes.
눈 감아
You'll be fine once you're clean.
깨끗하게 씻으면 괜찮아질 거야
Come on.
자
Come here.
이리 와
Let's wash your little tummy.
배도 씻자
Wash your tummy...
배도 씻어
You...
아니
-I'm sorry. -It's OK.
- 죄송해요 - 아니에요
Here, wipe yourself.
자, 닦아요
This is...
이건
its towel.
쟤 수건이에요
That's perfect.
그럼 잘됐네요
You can wipe yourselves together.
얘랑 같이 닦아요
Oh, it's shivering.
몸을 떠네요
Little doggy,
강아지야
you're actually white.
너 하얀색이었구나
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
let me adopt Ivory.
샤오바이를 나한테 맡겨 줘요
Ivory?
샤오바이요?
When did you name it?
이름 언제 지었어요?
Just now.
방금요
But...
근데
you don't look like
보기에는
someone who knows how to keep pets.
반려동물 잘 못 키우실 것 같은데요
So,
그러니까
I need you to help out.
린 선생님이 많이 도와줘야죠
Well...
그게…
There isn't much stuff at my place.
우리 집은 짐이 없어서
Lots of room for it to move around.
활동 공간이 넓어요
Alright then.
알겠어요
Be good, Ivory.
샤오바이, 착하지
I'll come see you again tomorrow morning.
내일 아침에 또 보러 올게
Don't worry.
걱정 마요
I can report
이 아이의 상태를
on its condition to you every day.
매일매일 보고드릴 테니까
Be good.
착하지
You have to behave tonight,
밤에 말 잘 들어야 해
you hear me?
알았지?
I'll come see you tomorrow.
내일 보러 올게
Open the door!
문 열어요
Wang Fa,
왕파
open the door.
문 좀 열어 줘요
Breakfast and daily necessities for Ivory.
샤오바이 아침이랑 생필품인데
I grabbed you breakfast on the way.
사는 김에 당신 것도 좀 샀어요
Let me do it. Go.
내가 할게요, 가요
Bacon, flatbread, fried dough sticks,
훈제 고기 호떡, 튀김 빵
egg yolk shumai, pork rib porridge, and soy milk.
달걀노른자, 찐만두 갈비죽, 두유까지
Your "on the way"
린 선생님의 '사는 김에'가
is quite the feast.
꽤 푸짐하네요
Enjoy your meal.
그럼 맛있게 먹어요
I'm going to work.
나 출근할게요
I'll help you.
내가 도와줄게요
What are you smiling about?
왜 웃어요?
I suddenly feel that
갑자기 든 생각인데
being injured isn't so bad.
다치는 것도 나쁘지 않은 것 같아요
The service fee will be added to your rent.
수고비는 월세에 추가할게요
Bye-bye, Ivory.
샤오바이, 안녕!
Speed up your cadence, Qin Ao.
친아오! 보속 올려
Make sure to lift your legs high.
높이 신경 쓰고
Fu Xinshu, remember to breathe while running.
푸신수, 뛸 때 호흡 잊지 마
Inhale for two steps,
두 걸음에 한 번씩
exhale for two steps.
들이마시고, 또 내쉬고
OK.
네
Lin Lu, lift your legs higher.
린루, 다리 높이 들어
Speed up your cadence.
보속 올리고
Widen your stride.
보폭도 넓게
For you guys.
마셔요
Thanks.
고마워요
Ms. Lin went to a meeting.
린 선생님은 회의하러 갔어요
I know.
알아요
What do you need me for?
저한테 무슨 볼일 있나요?
Thanks for finding Wanxing yesterday.
어제 완싱을 찾아줘서 고마워요
You didn't just come to say that, right?
그 얘기만 하려고 온 건 아닐 텐데요
I should've mentioned that we grew up together.
완싱이랑은 어렸을 때부터 친구라고 말씀드렸죠?
But actually, I didn't like her much then.
근데 사실 전 그때 걜 별로 안 좋아했어요
She was pretty,
예쁘고
cute, polite,
귀엽고
and even had good grades.
예의 바르고 성적도 좋았거든요
Basically everyone liked her.
거의 모든 애들이 다 완싱을 좋아했어요
She even had a fan club on the school forum
학교 게시판에 팬클럽까지 있었는데
that recorded a lot of her preferences.
걔가 뭘 좋아하는지 잔뜩 적혀 있었죠
Like how she
뭐
doesn't like cilantro
고수는 안 먹고
and loves the sweet and sour flavor.
새콤달콤한 걸 제일 좋아한다
Sounds ridiculous, doesn't it?
진짜 말도 안 되죠
I can imagine.
상상은 가네요
On the other hand, back then,
그에 비해 당시 저는
I had super short hair,
짧은 머리에
and because of my bad eyesight,
시력이 너무 안 좋아서
I wore thick glasses.
두꺼운 안경을 하고 다녔어요
No one really talked to me.
저한테 말 거는 애가 거의 없었죠
I remember once when
한번은
I couldn't hold back,
도저히 못 참고
and I fought
반에서
with the boy who loved to
유독 애들을 괴롭히던 남자애랑
bully others.
싸움이 붙었어요
I beat him right into the nurse's office.
양호실에 실려 갈 정도로 패줬거든요
But the homeroom teacher also punished me
담임 선생님은 저도 복도에
by making me stand in the hallway.
서 있으라고 하셨어요
Surprisingly, she came out and stood with me too.
근데 완싱도 벌을 서러 나왔더라고요
I thought she just came to laugh at me.
절 비웃으러 온 줄 알았는데
But she actually said,
저한테 그러는 거예요
"You're so cool.
너 진짜 멋있다
Can I be in your group next PE class?"
다음 체육 시간에 너랑 같은 조 해도 돼?
I got hurt here
그때 싸우다가
in that fight,
여길 다쳤는데
and it kept bleeding.
피가 계속 났거든요
No one noticed.
근데 아무도 몰랐어요
I didn't even realize myself.
저조차도요
But she noticed.
근데 완싱이 발견한 거예요
She was right there in the hallway,
그리고 복도에
squatting down to put a bandage on me.
쪼그려 앉아서 반창고를 붙여 줬어요
After that, we became good friends.
그 뒤로 우린 친한 친구가 됐죠
But then I transferred schools.
하지만 그 후에 제가 전학을 갔어요
Wanxing is very important to me.
완싱은 저한테 아주 중요해요
No less than to you.
나도 그래요
I care about Lin Wanxing at least
린완싱은 나한테도 중요해요
as much as you do.
그쪽 못지않게요
Li, Wang Fa.
샤오리, 왕파
The latest report for the group stage is out.
조별 리그 최신 경기 결과가 나왔어요
[Third round of the group stage]
[조별 리그 제3라운드]
Chuncheng Xinpeng and Yuzhou Yinxiang
춘청 신펑이랑 위저우 인샹이
played to a 2–2 draw.
2 대 2로 비겼어
We beat Yinxiang.
우리가 인샹을 이겼거
Yinxiang tied with Xinpeng.
인샹이 신펑이랑 비겼어
So it should be a piece of cake
그럼 신펑이랑 붙으면
for us to beat Xinpeng!
완전 껌 아니야?
Did you see that
융촨 헝주랑
Yongchuan Hengjiu beat Shenhai Yinbo
선하이 인보 경기 봤어?
by 9–0?
걔네 9 대 0으로 이겼어
Good thing our next opponent is Xinpeng.
우리 다음 상대가 춘청 신펑이라 다행이네
That's right.
맞아
You still have room for improvement.
너희 아직 발전 가능성이 있어
We can still advance by ranking second in points.
저희 승점 2위여도 진출하잖아요
Look at you two,
너희 진짜
so unambitious.
그것밖에 안 돼?
We're not the noobs we used to be.
우린 이제 예전의 뉴비가 아니야
Why can't we fight for first place?
왜 1등을 노리면 안 되는데?
Exactly.
맞아
What do you think, Coach?
코치님 생각은 어떠세요?
I think everyone can take a look
우선 각자
at your recent data.
최근 데이터를 한번 보자
Well,
여기
my high-intensity sprints
나 고강도 달리기가 15번에서
[Player Name] [First Test] [Second Test]
[선수 이름] [첫 테스트][두 번째 테스트]
went from 15 to 25 reps.
25번으로 늘었어
I finally won't hold everyone back.
이젠 팀에 민폐가 아니네
Still a bit behind me.
그래도 나 따라오려면 아직 멀었어
Many moves that you couldn't do before
예전에는 다들 못 했던 동작들이
can now be done
체력이 올라가면서
due to improved stamina.
지금은 다 가능해졌어
So,
그러니까
our current data
지금의 데이터라면
matches our current ambitions.
그런 욕심을 가져도 돼
We can fight for it.
한번 해볼 만해
Fight for it!
해 봐요
-Of course. -Let's go then.
- 두말하면 잔소리죠 - 해 봐요
Xinpeng's nothing!
신펑 그까짓 거
-Fight! -Let's fight then.
- 해 보자 - 한번 해 봐
Fight for it!
좋아
By the way,
참
remember not to let Ivory lick its wound
샤오바이 상처 핥지 못 하게 하고요
and feed it calcium tablets.
칼슘제도 챙겨 먹여요
I'm off.
먼저 들어갈게요
Wait.
잠깐만요
Aren't you going upstairs to see Ivory?
올라가서 샤오바이 안 봐요?
It's time to change its dressing.
약 갈아줘야 하는데
I might not be able
나 혼자서는
to handle it myself.
힘들 것 같아서요
Let's go.
가요
Be good, Ivory.
샤오바이, 착하지
Come, let me look at your wound.
상처 좀 보자
The wound is still a bit red.
상처가 아직 좀 빨갛네요
Let's apply some medicine.
약 발라야겠어요
Hold him down.
잡아줘요
OK.
네
Be good, Ivory.
샤오바이, 착하지
Good doggo.
착하다
I'll give you beef jerky after applying the medicine.
약 다 바르면 육포 줄게
It won't hurt, OK?
안 아파, 안 아파
It won't hurt.
안 아프다
-Let me blow on it. -Be good.
- 이리 와, 호 불어 줄게 - 착하지
♪ I caught your eyes ♪
♪ 난 네 눈빛을 포착했어 ♪
♪ On the summer night ♪
♪ 그 여름밤에 ♪
♪ Like stars that glow so bright ♪
♪ 눈부시게 반짝이던 별처럼 ♪
♪ A spark in my heart ♪
♪ 마음속 한 떨기의 불꽃이 ♪
♪ Lost in a dream secretly ♪
♪ 꿈속에서 조용히 사라져 갔어 ♪
♪ With the evening breeze ♪
♪ 저녁 바람이 ♪
You're blowing on my hair.
내 머리카락에 대고 불면 어떡해요?
Sorry.
미안해요
Ivory.
샤오바이
Beef jerky.
육포 먹어
Go.
가
Go play.
가서 놀고 있어
Ivory was likely an abandoned dog,
샤오바이는 주인한테 버려진 강아지 같아요
so he's traumatized.
그래서 마음에 상처가 있을 거예요
Spend more time with it.
평소에 자주 놀아주세요
Dogs can also have PTSD?
강아지도 외상 후 스트레스 장애가 있군요
What's wrong?
왜요?
I think it has done a boo-boo.
쟤 사고 친 것 같아요
I'll handle it.
내가 할게요
It's getting late.
늦었으니까
I'll head back.
이만 가볼게요
Bye-bye, Ivory.
샤오바이, 안녕!
Are you free this weekend?
주말에 시간 돼요?
This weekend?
주말이요?
I don't think so.
안 될 것 같은데요
Ivory needs a checkup.
샤오바이 건강 검진해야 하는데
I can't handle it alone.
나 혼자서는 힘들 것 같아서요
Can't handle it again?
또 힘들어요?
Coach Wang,
코치님
your hand is getting worse with treatment, huh?
코치님 손은 치료할수록 더 심해지는 것 같은데요
No, just in case.
아니에요 혹시 모르니까 그러죠
Why do I feel like you're trying to play me?
왜 이렇게 낚이는 기분이 들죠?
You're mistaken.
오해예요
Right, there's one more thing.
참, 한 가지 더 있어요
What is it?
뭔데요?
Are you booking me for the following weekend?
다다음 주 주말이라도 예약하시게요?
It's business.
진짜 중요한 일이에요
I want to show you something.
보여 줄 게 있거든요
What is it?
뭔데요?
Let's review the tapes of our game with Yuzhou Yinxiang.
위저우 인샹과의 경기 영상 한번 봐 줘요
Go back!
뒤로, 뒤로
Zheng Ren!
정런
Him! Go at him!
슛해, 슛!
Go at him!
슛해
What do you think?
어때요?
I noticed that
보니까
although Wen Chengye seems lazy sometimes
원청예가 평소에는 좀 게을러 보이고
and doesn't run much,
잘 안 뛰는데
at the crucial moment,
결정적인 순간에는
he always does his part methodically.
착실하게 제 몫을 다하더라고요
Look here.
여기 봐요
Our ball's been stolen,
우리 팀이 공을 뺏겼는데
but Wen Chengye didn't chase it.
원청예는 쫓아가지 않고
Instead, he dropped to backcourt
오히려 수비 진영으로 갔어요
to mark their defensive midfielder.
상대 수비형 미드필더를 막으려고요
So you mean...
그 말은…
He most likely
얘가요
anticipated it.
상대가 수비형 미드필더한테 패스할 걸
He predicted they'd pass to their defensive midfielder.
예측했을 가능성이 커요
So rather than wasting energy chasing the ball,
그러니까 힘 빼면서 쫓아가기보다
he thought about their next move and prepared
상대의 다음 수를 먼저 생각해서
in advance.
미리 대비한 거죠
A very smart choice.
아주 영리한 선택이에요
Wen Chengye has brains
원청예는 머리가 좋아요
and is bold enough,
배짱도 있고요
but he doesn't fit in with his teammates.
근데 팀원들과는 겉돌아요
You noticed, too,
선생님도 봤죠
that on the field,
경기장에서
he only plays by himself.
걔 혼자 멋대로만 뛰는 거
Even when his teammates signal him,
팀원이 사인을 보내도
he only plays according to his own judgment.
자기 판단에 따라서만 공을 차죠
So,
결국
he only seems to have joined us,
우리 팀에 들어온 것처럼 보이지만
but he has never really blended in.
사실은 전혀 어울리지 못했던 거네요
If he can build chemistry with his teammates,
만약 팀원들과 호흡을 맞출 수 있다면
it might elevate the whole team.
팀 전체를 바꿀 수도 있어요
I'll figure something out.
내가 방법을 찾아볼게요
Slow down.
천천히, 천천히
Nice one.
나이스!
-To Fu. -Come on.
- 신수 - 이리 와
Nice one!
나이스
-Here you go! -Go back!
- 자, 패스 - 뒤로 차
OK! Take a ten-minute break.
좋아, 10분 휴식한다
Go there. Go.
저쪽에 가자
What do you think of Wen Chengye?
네가 보기에 원청예 걔 어떤 것 같아?
He is
원청예는
a bit hard to approach.
성격이 좀 까칠하긴 한데요
But you can tell he likes playing football.
축구를 좋아하는 건 확실히 보여요
I think so too.
나도 그렇게 생각해
Fu Xinshu, I have a little plan
푸신수, 나한테 작은 계획이 하나 있는데
to help Wen Chengye
원청예가
integrate into the team better.
팀에 더 잘 어울리게 할 수 있어
Care to join me?
같이 해 볼래?
Of course.
당연히 좋죠
Why did Ms. Lin call us up here?
린 선생님이 왜 우리를 부르셨을까?
-I don't know. -Where is she?
- 나도 몰라 - 다 어디 갔어?
I don't know.
모르지
It's a bit cold today.
오늘 좀 춥네
Come on up.
올라와
Ms. Lin!
린 선생님은
-Ms. Lin. -I'm here.
- 린 선생님 - 나 여기 있어
Go, go, go!
가자
Ms. Lin.
선생님
Ms. Lin, what are you up to now?
선생님, 이번엔 또 뭐예요?
Calling us up here to catch a cold in the night?
여기로 불러서 찬바람 쐬게 할 것도 아니고
Is everyone here?
다 모였네
Today,
오늘은
we're going to solve
다 같이 아주 중대한 문제를
a very serious problem.
해결할 거야
According to the latest Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents,
최신 국민 식생활 지침에 따르면
our football team's late-night meals
우리 축구팀의 야식이
are very poor.
아주 열악해
How are they poor?
뭐가 열악한데요?
I propose
이제부터
a ban on instant noodles.
라면은 금지야
-W-Wait! No way! -No way.
그건 안 되죠
-I'm so hungry at night. -What will we eat then?
- 밤 되면 배고파요 - 그럼 저녁에 뭐 먹어요?
Besides, we're in a tournament now.
게다가 지금은 시합 기간이잖아요
We have extra training every day,
매일 추가 훈련도 해야 하고요
and the cafeteria is closed after.
훈련 끝나면 식당이 문을 닫는데
-There's nothing else to eat. -Yeah.
- 라면 아니면 뭘 먹어요? - 맞아요
But instant noodles lack nutrition.
라면은 영양가가 없잖니
You have matches coming up.
곧 시합인데
Instant noodles aren't enough.
라면만 먹어서 되겠어?
Does anyone second this?
재청할 사람
We always eat instant noodles at night.
밤에 맨날 라면만 먹으니까
Even three or four packs don't fill me up.
서너 개씩 먹어도 배가 안 부르잖아
One vote to second this?
제청에 한 표
Now, let's vote.
그럼 이제 표결에 들어간다
But instant noodles are tasty and convenient.
근데 라면이 맛있고 간편하잖아요
What else can we eat at night?
라면 안 먹으면 밤에 뭘 먹어요?
That's easy.
그게 뭐가 걱정이야?
We can cook ourselves.
직접 해 먹으면 되지
It's not like you haven't tasted my cooking.
제 요리 솜씨 못 본 것도 아니잖아요
Your food's actually a bit too greasy.
너희 집 음식 사실 좀 기름져
-Your food makes our muscles shrink. -I'll just eat instant noodles.
- 네 밥 먹으면 근육 떨어져 - 난 그냥 라면 먹을래
Why don't you consider the cost?
비용은 생각 안 해?
Where do we get so much money?
그 돈이 어디서 나는데?
Right.
맞아
To have a balanced diet and build muscle,
게다가 근육량은 늘리고 체지방은 줄여야 하잖아요
we need to have green and organic stuff.
당연히 친환경 유기농 식품을 먹어야지
Your standards are too high.
그 기준은 너무 높아
Can we meet them?
저희가 그 기준을 맞출 수 있을까요?
It's possible.
맞출 수 있어
We can grow our own vegetables.
우리가 직접 채소를 기르면 돼요
-Grow our own? -Who knows how to?
- 직접 기르라고요? - 할 줄 아는 사람 있어?
-How can we grow our own? -Grow them? Where?
- 아니, 어떻게 심어? - 심을 곳이 있겠어?
With such a big place,
이 넓은 땅이 있는데
can't we grow some vegetables?
채소 하나 못 심겠어?
Growing your vegetables and cooking yourselves,
직접 채소 길러서 직접 요리하면
all the things you just said can be achieved.
아까 말한 게 다 해결되잖아요
So, prospering through self-sufficiency by starting up
자급자족해서 살라는 거네
a little vegetable garden!
텃밭을 가꾸면서
We can grow tomatoes.
토마토 심어도 되겠다
Let's appoint a person in charge of the vegetable plot.
우리 텃밭 책임자를 정해요
It'll be easier to manage.
그래야 관리하기 편하죠
Wen Chengye,
원청예
can you be in charge?
혹시 책임자 맡아줄 수 있어?
It's decided, Wen Chengye.
그래, 원청예가 해
Do you agree?
동의하지?
If you don't agree,
동의 안 하면
how about joining Ms. Ju's physics competition class?
쥐 선생님의 물리 경시반으로 가야 해
♪ Time's passing by ♪
♪ 세월은 물처럼 ♪
♪ Nothing remains ♪
♪ 흔적도 없이 흘러가고 ♪
-Tomatoes. -Tomatoes? OK.
- 토마토 - 토마토, 그래
♪ All the dreamers awake alone ♪
♪ 함께 꿈꾸던 우리 쉽사리 잠들지 못하네 ♪
♪ Shadows above ♪
♪ 때로는 먹구름이 드리우고 ♪
How about baby bok choy?
배추는 어때?
♪ Rain falls around ♪
♪ 축축한 빗물이 삶의 구석구석을 적셔도 ♪
It's easy to store when it grows up,
이게 다 자라면 보관하기도 편하고
♪ In your arms ♪
♪ 네 품 안에서 ♪
♪ We become one ♪
♪ 평행하던 우리 세상은 마침내 하나가 돼 ♪
and you can eat it all year round.
사계절 내내 먹을 수 있잖아
♪ Through day and night ♪
♪ 낮과 밤이 흘러도 ♪
Bok choy then.
그럼 배추로 하자
OK.
알았어
♪ I can see you ♪
♪ 너의 눈동자 속에서 ♪
♪ In my eyes ♪
♪ 진짜 나를 마주해 ♪
Go, go, go!
- 가자
-Let's get to work. -Come on, let's start.
- 일해 - 자, 시작해
♪ Just hold me tight ♪
♪ 꼭 안아 주기만 하면 ♪
♪ Look into my soul so deeply ♪
♪ 너의 시선은 내 영혼 깊숙이 닿아 ♪
Go, go, go.
가자
Pour the soil in first.
먼저 흙부터 붓고
Come on!
자, 이리 와
Fertilizer! Fertilizer!
비료, 비료
♪ Rainbow sunlight ♪
♪ 무지갯빛 후광 아래 ♪
Lin Lu.
린루
Chen Jianghe.
천싱허
♪ Painful tears are gone ♪
♪ 아픈 지난날은 어제가 되고 ♪
-OK.
- 응 - 그래
Zhi Hui.
즈후이
♪ Wonderful days ♪
♪ 반짝이는 아름다운 꿈은 ♪
♪ Are so close to me ♪
♪ 내게는 닿을 수 없는 것 같지만 ♪
♪ Memories fly ♪
♪ 추억은 스쳐 가는 한숨처럼 ♪
Stir it like this, right?
이렇게 그냥 섞으면 되는 건가?
♪ Leave them all behind ♪
♪ 지난 상처를 다정히 어루만지고 ♪
Yes.
응
Is fertilizer white?
비료가 흰색이야?
♪ Just take my hand and stay with me ♪
♪ 우리는 손을 맞잡은 채 영원히 함께해 ♪
Yes, yes.
응, 맞아
Wen Chengye, how much fertilizer do I add?
원청예, 이 비료 얼마나 넣어야 해?
Two spoons are enough.
두 숟가락이면 돼
Two spoons.
두 숟가락
Wen Chengye, is this enough water?
원청예 물은 이 정도면 될까?
Wait, I'm coming.
잠깐만, 금방 갈게
What's this?
뭐 해?
Do I add more water?
물 더 부어야 하나?
♪ Time's passing by ♪
♪ 세월은 물처럼 ♪
Is it OK to stir it like this?
이렇게 섞으면 되지?
♪ Nothing remains ♪
♪ 흔적도 없이 흘러가고 ♪
Yes.
돼
Wen Chengye, we should add fertilizer here, right?
원청예 여기 비료 넣어야 하지?
♪ All the dreamers awake alone ♪
♪ 함께 꿈꾸던 우리 쉽사리 잠들지 못하네 ♪
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
♪ Shadows above ♪
♪ 때로는 먹구름이 드리우고 ♪
Well,
아니
Coach is injured,
코치님은 다치셔서
♪ Rain falls around ♪
♪ 축축한 빗물이 삶의 구석구석을 적셔도 ♪
so it's fine that he doesn't help.
안 도와주시는 건 괜찮은데
♪ In your arms ♪
♪ 네 품 안에서 ♪
But you...
선생님은 좀…
♪ We become one ♪
♪ 평행하던 우리 세상은 마침내 하나가 돼 ♪
Me? What about me?
나? 내가 뭐?
♪ Through day and night ♪
♪ 낮과 밤이 흘러도 ♪
I'm the investor of this little garden.
나 이 텃밭의 투자자거든
♪ I can see you ♪
♪ 너의 눈동자 속에서 ♪
Have you ever seen investors getting their hands dirty?
돈도 내고 일까지 하는 투자자 본 적 있어?
♪ In my eyes ♪
♪ 진짜 나를 마주해 ♪
♪ Rainbow sunlight ♪
♪ 무지갯빛 후광 아래 ♪
Stir it a bit more.
좀 더 섞어야겠어
♪ Painful tears are gone ♪
♪ 아픈 지난날은 어제가 되고 ♪
It's still dry.
좀 말랐네
-Be gentle! -Slowly.
- 살살해 - 살살
♪ Wonderful days ♪
♪ 반짝이는 아름다운 꿈은 ♪
I'm tired.
피곤해
♪ Are so close to me ♪
♪ 내게는 닿을 수 없는 것 같지만 ♪
Guys...
얘들아
♪ Memories fly ♪
♪ 추억은 스쳐 가는 한숨처럼 ♪
I found some seeds
이건 내가 구해 온
♪ Leave them all behind ♪
♪ 지난 상처를 다정히 어루만지고 ♪
suitable for planting.
심기 좋은 씨앗이야
♪ Just take my hand and stay with me ♪
♪ 우리는 손을 맞잡은 채 영원히 함께해 ♪
-Let me see. -A pot of Chinese eggplants.
- 어디 봐봐 - 가지네
I want these scallions.
난 쪽파 할래
Wen Chengye.
원청예
What are these two bags without labels?
이 두 봉지는 이름표가 없는데 뭐야?
Let me see.
어디 봐봐
The light yellow ones are Facing Heaven hot peppers.
연노란색은 하늘초고
This should be bell peppers.
이건 아마 파프리카일 거야
You can always count on a top student.
역시 모범생이라니까
Come on.
자
Let me help you.
내가 도와줄게
Looks like your instruction is
린 선생님의 교육이
making great progress.
효과가 톡톡하네요
Of course.
그럼요
Everyone must be thirsty.
다들 목마르지?
Have some drinks.
자, 음료수 마셔
Yogurt for everyone.
한 사람당 요구르트 하나씩
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
감사합니다, 선생님
-It's sweet and sour. -Thanks, Ms. Lin!
- 달콤새콤 맛있어 - 감사합니다, 린 선생님
-Here, here.
- 자, 마셔 - 고맙습니다, 선생님
Divide it yourselves.
알아서들 나눠 가지세요
-Lu, get me one. -So good. One more.
- 린루, 나도 한 개만 줘 - 진짜 맛있네
Here, here.
이리 와
Have two.
두 병 마셔
Another one.
한 병 더!
Come on!
이리 와
The watering begins!
이제 물 놀이 시간이야
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪
♪ Running towards you ♪
♪ 널 향해 달려가 ♪
♪ I keep moving fearlessly ♪
♪ 두려움 없이 앞으로 나아가 ♪
Come on!
이리 와, 붙어
Let's take a photo.
사진 찍자
♪ Walk side by side ♪
♪ 나란히 함께 ♪
Ready?
나 왔어
Wait! Hang on!
잠깐만, 잠깐만
♪ Become ourselves ♪
♪ 나 자신이 되어 ♪
Wen Chengye!
원청예
♪ Amid the storm ♪
♪ 폭풍 속에서 ♪
♪ As our breaths slowly intertwine ♪
♪ 천천히 다가오는 숨결, 숨결 ♪
Hurry!
빨리 와
Don't be such a loner!
왜 혼자 떨어져 있어?
Hurry up.
빨리
Three, two, one!
셋, 둘, 하나
♪ Heartbeats alternating ♪
♪ 교차하는 심장 소리 ♪
♪ The stars are shining ♪
♪ 반짝이는 별빛 ♪
♪ For you ♪
♪ 널 위해서라면 ♪
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪